Drinker, Sophie Hutchinson, 1888-1967. Papers, 1917-1967: A Finding Aid
Papers, 1917-1967
1351; Phon-4
Schlesinger Library, Radcliffe Institute
Sophie (Hutchinson) Drinker, 1888-1967
2 linear ft. (2 cartons), 2 phonograph records
Correspondence, etc., of Sophie Hutchinson Drinker, musician, civic volunteer, historian, author, and feminist.
Accession number: 1351
The collection of Sophie Drinker, wife of Henry S. Drinker of the Drinker Library of Choral Music, and national consultant of the Schlesinger Library, 1955-1967, was received in April, 1968.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
The collection consists of notes and articles on women's participation in music, music for women's chorus, and notes and glass lantern slides on goddesses and priestesses. Also included is a thesis by Mary Milbank Brown on goddesses in music.
There are additional papers at the Schlesinger Library. See Sophie Hutchinson Drinker, 1888-1967. Additional papers, 1911-1983 ( 84-M96 ).
CONTAINER LIST
Carton 1: 1-27
Carton 2: 28-29
Phon 4
INVENTORY
- Printed and ms material re women's chorus., 1-9v:
  - Catalogue of music for women's chorus., 1.
  - SHD's articles on choral literature for women's chorus., 2.
  - Re music for women's chorus and correspondence, 1937-1950., 3.
  - Notebook of notes and correspondence re women's choral music, ca. 1954, 4.
  - Notebook of notes and correspondence re women's choral music, ca. 1954, 5.
  - Kathi Meyer's Choral Singing of Women, ts. translation in English, 6.
  - Kathi Meyer's Der Chorische Gesang der Frauen (1917), 7v.
  - Arthur Ware Locke, Selected List of Choruses for Women's Voices, (1927), annotated by SHD., 8v.
  - Arthur Ware Locke, ibid (revised, 1946), 9v.
- Newspaper clipping (in Russian) and notes re women in Russian music., 10v.
- Correspondence between Mary Beard, Sophie Drinker and Mary Milbank Brown re goddesses in music, 1949-1956., 11.
- Mary Milbank Brown, "On Goddesses", ts. n.d., 12.
- Mary Milbank Brown, "On Goddesses", ts. n.d., 13.
- Mary Milbank Brown, "On Goddesses", ts. n.d., 14.
- Mary Milbank Brown, "On Goddesses", ts. n.d., 15.
- Mary Milbank Brown, "On Goddesses", ts. n.d., 16.
- Mary Milbank Brown, "On Goddesses", ts. n.d., 17.
- SHD's correspondence and notes re St. Cecilia, 18.
- St. Cecilia with interesting symbols, 19.
- Pictures of forerunner of St. Cecilia, correspondence and notes., 20.
- St. Cecilia, with and without organ, 21.
- Reprints of articles (not SHD's) and correspondence re St. Cecilia 1962, 22.
- Correspondence re St. Cecilia, 1956-1957, 23.
- SHD's article on St. Cecilia, ts, 24.
- Notes re "Deified church and theologia musica" includes letter from Trapp Family Singers, 1954, 25.
- SHD's "Relation of Deities to Music", correspondence and notes, also reprints (not SHD's)., 26.
- SHD "Laws on Rape and Abortion", 1967, 27.
- Notecards on music for women's chorus, 28.
- Large collection of glass lantern slides and engraving blocks, illustrating women's and deities' participation in music., 29.
- Russian folksongs, phonograph record., Phon 4: 1.
- Russian folksongs, phonograph record., Phon 4: 2.
Additional catalog entries
Beard Mary (Ritter), 1876-1958; Brown, Mary Milbank; Abortion; Goddesses; Music; Women in music